Suraj Anand

Email: surya13493@gmail.com Contact No.: +91 8860226180 Address- Gurugram, India.

Career Summary

Focused and quick-learning Web developer with 2 years of experience in Real-time data monitoring system, E-commerce portals, & Informative static websites development for various domestic and international clients. Experience in designing, building infrastructure, client-server architectures and web services.

Technical Skills

- Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, PHP, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap.
- Development: WAMP, LAMP, Heroku, Bitbucket, Git.
- CMS: WordPress, Magento(Beginner).
- Database Systems: MySQL, PostgreSQL.
- Operating System: Windows, Linux.

Work Experience

Projects: https://suraj-anand.herokuapp.com

Web developer & UI Designer, Digital Projects, Jan 2018 - Present

- Designed and built effective and attractive user interfaces for a variety of platforms
- Developed E-commerce & Informative Static websites for Domestic & International clients.
- Participated in meetings in order to transform client needs into proposed product designs.
- Worked on several projects and provided end-to-end solutions to clients.

Software Developer & UI Designer, Soreva Energy, Dec 2016 – Dec 2017

- Developed a PV Solar Real-Time data monitoring system for National Institute of Solar Energy campus.
- Designed an application to monitor SRRA(Solar Radiation Resource Assessment) station for analysis of meteorological data in real time from all sites stations from a single centralized platform for NIWE.
- Developed the application with these salient features: Dashboards, Data Visualization, Reports, Export functionality, Real-time solar plant performance monitoring & Environmental contribution.
- Worked with team to develop a proprietary, secure, and centralized database.
- Developed application prototypes and participated in client meetings.

UI Designer, Avencher, Sep 2016 – Dec 2016

- Designed and built effective and attractive user interfaces for a variety of platforms.
- Developed Informative Static websites.
- Worked on several projects and provided end-to-end solutions to clients.

Professional Qualification

• B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering, United Group of Institution, Allahabad, 2012-2016.

Training and Certificate Details

- Core PHP, Udemy, 2018.
- WordPress, Udemy, 2018.
- MTA: Database Fundamentals Certified 2016 Certificate
- MTA: Java Development Certified 2014